chalet-hire.com 2018-12-28

# Privacy Policy | Chalet-Hire.com

We are serious about protecting the privacy of our users. This Privacy Policy describes how we use and protect your personal data. It applies to Chalet-Hire.com (which we have called the “Site” in this Policy).

This Site is operated by Chalet-Hire.

The terms “users” or “you” as used in this Privacy Policy, refer to both travellers, who use the Site to look for properties to rent, and members who join the Site and list their properties for rent.

We use information collected about you as explained in this Privacy Policy. The Site may contain links to third party websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those websites. Therefore, please read carefully any privacy policies on those websites before either agreeing to their terms or using those websites. Unless we explain otherwise in this Policy, the words and phrases used in this Policy have the same meaning as in the Terms and Conditions of Use - available at **[Terms & Conditions](http://www.chalet-hire.com/pages/index/terms-and-conditions)**.

By providing information to us when subscribing, sending enquiries or otherwise using the Site, you expressly agree to this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy was last updated on 26 October 2011. This Privacy Policy applies from that date. We may occasionally amend this Privacy Policy to reflect regulatory requirements, advances in technology, Site updates and changes in our information collection and disclosure practices. Any new policy will automatically be effective when it is published on the website. You should therefore return here regularly to view our most up to date Privacy Policy. You should also print a copy for your records.

**Who processes your personal data, and where?**

Your personal data (also referred to as personal information) - that is, data that identifies you, or from which you are identifiable - will be collected, processed, stored and used by us, and passed to and processed by other data processors acting under contract with us.

**The information we gather**

At various times you may give your personal data to us. For example, in order to process a request or enquiry from you, we may need to know all or some of the following: your full name, address, telephone number, email address, and, in the case of a member's listing, a method of payment. You may also give personal data to us at other times, such as when registering on the Site or when creating an advert or listing for a property. We may also gather information from cookies or web beacons. You can find out more about how cookies or web beacons operate in the relevant section of this Policy below. We also collect IP addresses, mobile device identifier details, your location, navigation and click-stream data, the time of accessing the Site, properties you viewed, what you searched for, the duration of your visit, and other details of your activity on the Site. For further details on how we collect personal data, see Surveys and Newsletters below. We obtain data from you either by you inputting your personal details, by the automatic collection of information about you as you use the Site, or from third parties. Third party information may include credit information which we use to prevent and detect fraud, information from your mobile provider if you are accessing the Site over a mobile device or information from a third party such as a social media or travel opinions site where you have asked us to share your data with them.

**How we use your personal data**

Our primary purpose in collecting your personal data is to provide you with the services you request and those which we believe will optimise your use of the Site. You agree that we may use your personal data for the following purposes:

  * For the services or support you request;
  * To contact you from time to time with user or service updates;
  * To send other messages that help us provide our services on the Site;
  * To assist people you have done business with. For example if you are an owner and a traveller who has booked or enquired with you needs your details we may pass them on; if you are a traveller and an owner you have booked or enquired with needs to contact you we may give them your details;
  * To customise, measure and improve our services, content and advertising;
  * To promote services related to the Site or those of the Chalet-Hire group and/or our affiliates including services related to travel insurance or damage protection products ;
  * To compare information for accuracy, and verify it with third parties;
  * To prevent, investigate or prosecute activity we determine to be potentially illegal, unlawful or harmful and
  * To enforce our Privacy Policy and/or our Terms or for any other purpose referenced herein or therein.

We collate statistics about Site traffic, sales and other commercial information which we pass onto third parties to assist us in improving the services we provide to you.

We also use demographic information to tailor the Site and we share that information with third parties so that they can build up a better picture of our customer base and general consumer trends.

If you are a member, we will also be able to contact you about your account and your use of our services.

**How we may disclose your personal data**

We may disclose your personal data to enforce our policies, or where we are permitted to do so by applicable law, such as in response to a request by a law enforcement or governmental authority, or in connection with actual or proposed litigation, or to protect our property, people and other rights.

We may also share your personal data with:

  * Another member if you have done business with them;
  * A third party performing services on our behalf;

In the event that Chalet-Hire.com is sold, or some of its assets transferred to a third party, your personal information, as a valuable asset, may also be transferred. However, use of your personal information will remain subject to this Privacy Policy, unless you agree otherwise. Similarly, your personal information may be passed on to a successor in interest in the event of a liquidation or administration.

Newsletters:

If you sign up as a member on the Site, you may receive our "Owner" newsletter, which is an integral part of the services we provide. Traveller users of the Site may be given the option to receive our "Traveller" newsletter when they register with us. We may offer different newsletters from time to time intended to enhance the services we offer. Users may cancel their subscription to these newsletters at any time, although it may take a short while for the changes in your preferences to become effective.

Surveys:

We may also use surveys to collect information about our users. From time to time, we request users' input in order to evaluate potential features and services. The decision to answer a survey is completely yours. We use information gathered from surveys to improve our services.

Enquiries:

Travellers may send enquiries to members via clickable links on the listings on the Site. If you choose to send an enquiry through these links, your personal information, including your email address and any other information you supply, will be visible to the member in question so that they might reply directly to you. Your details may also be sent to us and we may have access to those communications even if you contact the member directly. Additionally those messages may be hosted on, be processed by or transmit through our servers. If you call the member, you may be asked to leave a return telephone number. Do not share information in the email or phone call that you are not prepared to allow them and Chalet-Hire.com group to have, including, but not limited to, credit card and bank account information. Enquiries can be sent to the individual member you selected and to our system. The resulting enquiry is available for review by the member to whom it was initially addressed, who may share past enquiry information, or information related to past stays including your contact details with members. We may also from time to time, use third party email servers to send and track receipt of enquiry emails, and analyse the pattern of enquiry usage reported by these third party tracking systems.

**How Do We Protect Your Personal Information Once We Have It?**

We take reasonable technical and organisational measures to guard against unauthorised or unlawful processing of your personal data and against accidental loss or destruction of, or damage to, your personal data. While no system is completely secure, we believe the measures implemented by the Site reduce our vulnerability to security problems to a level appropriate to the type of data involved. We have security measures in place to protect our user database and access to this database is restricted internally. However, it remains your responsibility:

  * To protect against unauthorised access to your use of the Site;
  * To ensure no-one else uses the Site while your machine is "logged on" to the Site service (including by logging on to your machine through a mobile, Wi-Fi or shared access connection your are using);
  * To log off or exit from the Site when not using it;
  * Where relevant, to keep your password or other access information secret. Your password and log in details are personal to you and should not be given to anyone else or used to provide shared access for example over a network;
  * To not share your log-in credentials with third parties promoting products, websites and applications that request the credentials for the purpose of building a listing or profile for you on such third party products, websites or applications using information from your Chalet-Hire.com listing; and

If you have asked us to share data with third party sites (a site not operated by Chalet-Hire.com), we cannot guarantee that their servers will be secure. Credit or direct card information is generally stored by our credit card processing partners and we ask them to keep that data secure. We also use third parties to help us optimise our Site flow, content and advertising (see below).

Note that, despite the measures taken by us and the third parties we engage, the internet is not always secure. As a result others may nevertheless unlawfully intercept or access private transmissions or data.

**What are Cookies, Web Beacons and Clear GIFs and Why Do We Use Them?**

A "cookie" is a small file placed on your hard drive by some of our web pages. We, or third parties we do business with, may use cookies to help us analyse our web page flow, customise our services, content and advertising, measure promotional effectiveness and promote trust and security. Cookies are commonly used on most major transactional websites in much the same way we use them here at our Site.

Even if you are only browsing the Site, certain information (including computer and connection information, browser type and version, operating system and platform details, the time of accessing the Site) is automatically collected about you. This information will be collected every time you access the Site and it will be used for the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy.

An easy way of reducing the information cookies collect from your devise is often to change the settings in your browser. If you do that you should know that (a) your use of the Site may be adversely affected (and possibly entirely prevented), (b) your experience of this and other sites that use cookies to enhance or personalise your experience may be adversely affected, and (c) you may not be presented with advertising that reflects the way that you use our and other sites.

We gather and share information concerning the use of the Site by members and travellers with one or more third-party tracking companies for the purpose of reporting statistics. To do this, some of the pages you visit on our Site use electronic images placed in the web page code, called pixel tags (also called "clear GIFs" or "Web Beacons") that can serve many of the same purposes as cookies.

Web beacons may be used to track the traffic patterns of users from one page to another in order to maximize web traffic flow. Our third-party advertising service providers may also use web beacons to recognise you when you visit the Site and to help determine how you found the Site.

**Phishing or False emails**

If you receive an unsolicited email that appears to be from us or one of our members that requests personal information (such as your credit card, login, or password), or that asks you to verify or confirm your account or other personal information by clicking on a link, that email was likely to have been sent by someone trying to unlawfully obtain your information, sometimes referred to as a "phisher" We do not ask for this type of information in an email. Do not provide the information or click on the link. Please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#7811161e17381b1019141d0c5510110a1d561b1715) if you get an email like this.

**How do I correct or update my information?**

You can see any personal information processed by us. The best way of seeing this if you are an Owner is to log on to your account. You can see your basic details and correct or update them from your control panel at any time to suit you. We also want to give you the opportunity to identify any inaccuracies in any information we hold about you. Where possible, if we are told about an inaccuracy of any personal information, we will make appropriate corrections. You can ask to see, update or amend any information we hold on you by emailing us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#563f38303916353e373a33227b3e3f24337835393b).

**How do I opt-out of receiving marketing communications from you?**

You may opt-out of receiving marketing communications from us by the following means:

1\. Email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#422b2c242d02212a232e27366f2a2b30276c212d2f)

**How long will we keep your personal data?**

We will retain your personal data only as long as is necessary for the purposes to which you consent under the Terms and Conditions and this Privacy Policy, or as is required by applicable law, and then we will delete it.

**How do I contact you?**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this Site, or your dealings with this Site, please email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#452c2b232a05262d24292031682d2c37206b262a28).
